Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jeffweiner08 (LinkedIn) www.linkedin.com/ (Company)

Top Skills
Leadership
Entrepreneurship
Strategy

Jeff Weiner

Executive Chairman at LinkedIn

San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

Jeff Weiner is the executive chairman of LinkedIn, where he continues to help LinkedIn realize its vision of creating economic opportunity for every member of the global workforce. He'll also continue to mentor and coach the leadership team, advise on key strategic initiatives, and help to represent the company externally. In addition to his ongoing work at LinkedIn, Jeff is focused on investing, coaching and his philanthropic work, including helping to ensure that compassion is taught and practiced in every primary school in the U.S.

Prior to becoming executive chairman in June 2020, Jeff was the CEO of LinkedIn. During his 11-year tenure, LinkedIn grew its membership base from 33M to more than 690M, increased its revenue from \$78M to over \$7.9B and expanded the team from 338 employees to over 16,000.

Also, presently resides on the board of directors for Intuit, Donorschoose.org and Everfi, an ed tech company with which he cofounded The Compassion Project, a non-profit whose mission is to ensure compassion is taught in every elementary school in the U.S.

Additionally, an active early and growth stage investor through his Next Play Ventures fund and separately, the newly created Concrete Rose Capital fund, focused on investing in diverse founders, startups serving underserved communities and/or building diverse teams.

Prior to LinkedIn, was an Executive in Residence at Accel Partners and Greylock Partners. Primarily focused on advising the leadership teams of the firm's existing consumer technology portfolio companies while also working closely with the firm's partners to evaluate new investment opportunities.

Previously served in key leadership roles at Yahoo! for over seven years, most recently as the Executive Vice President of Yahoo!'s Network Division managing Yahoo's consumer web product portfolio, including Yahoo's Front Page, Mail, Search, and Media products.

Experience

LinkedIn

11 years 9 months

Executive Chairman
June 2020 - Present (3 months)

Help LinkedIn realize its vision of creating economic opportunity for every member of the global workforce. Continue to mentor and coach the leadership team, advise on key strategic initiatives, and help to represent the company externally with customers, partners, governments, and the media.

CEO

December 2008 - June 2020 (11 years 7 months)

Over 11 year tenure as CEO, LinkedIn grew its membership base from 33M to more than 690M, increased its revenue from \$78M to \$7.9B and expanded the team from 338 employees to over 16,000.

Next Play Ventures Founding Partner 2014 - Present (6 years)

San Francisco Bay Area

Our mission is to coach and invest in entrepreneurial leaders building world-class, purpose-driven organizations. Focus primarily on early stage and growth opportunities, e.g., Brex, Figma, Notion, Headspace, Scale, Wildlife Interactive, Vox Media, Cameo, Seesaw, Ginger.io, Brilliant, The Browser Company, Trala, Esusu and more. Previous exits include Slack (IPO) and Cloudera (IPO).

Concrete Rose Capital
Founding LP, Investment Committee
October 2019 - Present (11 months)
San Francisco Bay Area

Advisor and member of the investment committee for this newly created early stage fund and foundation focused on empowering diverse founders, start-ups serving underserved communities, and companies committed to building diverse teams.

Intuit
Member, Board of Directors
April 2012 - Present (8 years 5 months)
Mountain View, CA

Intuit is a leading provider of innovative business and financial management solutions for small and medium-sized businesses, consumers, accounting professionals and financial institutions.

DonorsChoose Member, Board of Directors 2007 - Present (13 years)

One of the web's leading philanthropic marketplaces, designed to enable teachers to upload classroom projects in need of funding, and for anyone to select and fund a project.

EVERFI

Member Board Of Directors September 2017 - Present (3 years) Washington D.C. Metro Area

Partnered with this innovative educational coursework and platform provider to develop and distribute The Compassion Project, an initiative designed to ensure compassion is taught in every primary school in the U.S.

Boys & Girls Clubs of the Peninsula Member, Advisory Board 2011 - Present (9 years)

BGCP's mission is to help its members develop the academic and life skills they need to complete high school ready for college and career.

BGCP serves youth in grades K–12 at nine locations: three clubhouses and six school sites in East Palo Alto, Menlo Park, and Redwood City, where over half the youth drop out of high school. While most youth development organizations select the young people whom they serve, BGCP serves all youth. The organization has grown rapidly over the past five years and now serves 2,000 active members at its nine sites.

Venture For America Member, Advisory Board 2012 - Present (8 years) Innovative fellowship program that places top college graduates in start-ups for two years in low-cost U.S. cities to generate job growth and train the next generation of entrepreneurs.

Malaria No More Member, Board of Directors 2007 - December 2015 (8 years)

Non-profit organization with the mission to eradicate the millions of preventable and treatable deaths due to malaria. Working in conjunction with the United Nations Millennium Development Goals.

Accel Partners

Executive in Residence

September 2008 - June 2009 (10 months)

Greylock
Executive in Residence
September 2008 - June 2009 (10 months)

Yahoo!

7 years 2 months

Executive Vice President Network Division February 2007 - June 2008 (1 year 5 months)

Led a team of over 3,000 employees, managing products reaching over 500 million consumers, and overseeing a P&L responsible for roughly \$3 billion in annual revenue. Helped drive the Network's Open and Social strategy and growth of the company's category-leading consumer web products, including Yahoo's Front Page, Mail, Search, and Media products, e.g. News, Sports, Finance, Entertainment.

Previously, was part of the Search leadership team that directed the acquisition and integration of Inktomi, AltaVista, FAST as well as the development of Yahoo! Search Technology. Oversaw development of Yahoo! Answers, and led the acquisitions of Flickr and del.icio.us. Helped lead the team formed to revitalize the company's Search Marketing efforts.

From 2001 to 2002, oversaw Corporate Development at Yahoo!, responsible for the development and modification of overall corporate and individual business unit strategy and M&A.

Senior Vice President, Search and Marketplace September 2002 - February 2007 (4 years 6 months) Sunnyvale, CA

Senior Vice President Corporate Development May 2001 - September 2002 (1 year 5 months) Sunnyvale, CA

Windsor Media
Founding Partner
June 2000 - April 2001 (11 months)

Warner Bros. Studios 5 years 7 months

Vice President Online September 1998 - March 2000 (1 year 7 months)

Helped oversee Warner Bros.' online efforts, including Warner Bros. Online and Entertaindom (one of the web's first original entertainment destination sites).

Director, Online April 1997 - September 1998 (1 year 6 months) Burbank, CA

Manager, Online April 1996 - April 1997 (1 year 1 month) Burbank, CA

Senior Analyst, Corporate Development September 1994 - April 1996 (1 year 8 months) Burbank, CA

Responsible for M&A evaluation, new business development, etc. In December, 1994, wrote the initial business plan for Warner Bros. Online. Division was approved and created in July, 1995.

Braxton Associates 2 years 1 month

Senior Analyst September 1993 - September 1994 (1 year 1 month) Boston

Analyst for strategic management consulting division of Deloitte & Touche. Case work included scenario planning, international expansion, brand

consolidation, and new distribution strategies across multiple industries including food, health care, and energy.

Analyst

September 1992 - September 1993 (1 year 1 month)

Boston, MA

Education

The Wharton School

Bachelor of Science, Economics · (1988 - June 1992)